Will you follow me... one last time?
The Hobbit: The Battle of the Five Armies is a action,
adventure, fantasy film directed by Peter Jackson.
Following Smaug's attack on Laketown, Bilbo and the dwarves try to defend Erebor's mountain of
treasure from others who claim it: the men of the ruined Laketown and the elves of Mirkwood.
Meanwhile an army of Orcs led by Azog the Defiler is marching on
Erebor, fueled by the rise of the dark lord Sauron.
Dwarves, elves and men must unite, and the hope for
Middle-Earth falls into Bilbo's hands.
Gandalf the Grey, played by Ian McKellen.
Bilbo Baggins, played by Martin Freeman.
Thorin Oakenshield, played by Richard Armitage.
Legolas, played by Orlando Bloom.
Tauriel, played by Evangeline Lilly.
Bard, played by Luke Evans.
The Hobbit: The Battle of the Five Armies is a 2014 epic high fantasy adventure film directed by Peter
Jackson from a screenplay by Fran Walsh, Philippa Boyens, Jackson, and Guillermo del Toro.
It is based on the 1937 novel The Hobbit by J.
The sequel to 2013's The Hobbit: The Desolation of Smaug, the film is the final instalment in The
Hobbit trilogy, acting as a prequel to Jackson's The Lord of the Rings trilogy (2001–2003).
The film's story concludes the adventure of the titular hobbit Bilbo Baggins and Thorin Oakenshield's company of dwarves, who take possession of the treasure within
the Lonely Mountain as factions of dwarves, elves and men clash over it, while the orc Azog the Defiler and his forces make their move upon them.
The film stars Martin Freeman, Ian McKellen, Richard Armitage, Evangeline Lilly, Luke Evans, Lee Pace, Benedict Cumberbatch, Ken
Stott, Aidan Turner, Dean O'Gorman, Billy Connolly, Graham McTavish, James Nesbitt, Stephen Fry, and Ryan Gage.
The ensemble cast also features Cate Blanchett, Ian Holm,
Christopher Lee, Hugo Weaving, and Orlando Bloom.
It was Holm and Lee's final live-action roles and final film released during their respective
lifetimes, although they would both provide voice performances in subsequent works.
As of 2026, it is also Peter Jackson's last fictional feature.
The Hobbit: The Battle of the Five Armies premiered in London on 1 December 2014, and was released on
11 December in New Zealand and on 17 December in the United States, by Warner Bros.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and grossed $962.2 million
worldwide, making it the second-highest-grossing film of 2014.
It received numerous accolades, including being nominated for
Best Sound Editing at the 87th Academy Awards.
The film explores themes of gold, corruption,
based on novel or book, elves, dwarf.
The tone is dark.